

MD. RAKIBUL ISLAM

Software Engineer

☐ rakib1708@gmail.com [] +88 016 1707 5540 in /rakibhstu () /rakibdevs House # 02, Road # 06, Section 6, Mirpur, Dhaka

OBJECTIVE

Hard-working individual with **5 years** of experience in PHP, Laravel, Vue.js, JavaScript, MySQL and REST API development, as well as ability to communicate effectively in a team setting, and possessing a strong willingness to learn.

EXPERIENCES

MBM GROUP Mirpur DOHS, Dhaka

Software Engineer

2020 - Present

- Develop, test and implement new software programs, Data Communication Processes and User Interfaces.
- Test, maintain and recommend software improvements to ensure strong functionality and optimization.
- Facilitate root cause analysis of system issues

Muktiventures Ltd. Kalabagan, Dhaka

Software Developer

2019 -2020

- Implementing new features and ideas in a garment's ERP with HR, Merchandising and Commercial module.
- Participated in a highly collaborative team environment, contributed to all phases of the development lifecycle using Agile methodologies.

ITDEAL Rangpur

Software Developer 2018 -2019

- Developing inventory, hr and pathological management systems.
- Writing algorithm and coding with Laravel, Codelgniter, JavaScript, jQuery

VALOBAZAR ENET Dinajpur

Software Developer

2016 -2018

- Developed embedded application software for .an e-commerce and Chinese language learning tool.
- Led design and participated in the development of web application with Magento

SKILLS

Programming Language: PHP, Java, JavaScript, C

Framework: PHP - Laravel, Codelgniter, Symphony, WordPress, Magento

JavaScript – Vue.js, React.js

Database: MySQL, MongoDB, Oracle

PROJECTS

RADMIN LARAVEL STARTER KIT

2020

Link: http://radmin.rakibhstu.com/

Radmin is a Laravel Kickstarter with REST API, Advanced user, roles & permission management, Serverside Datatable, Datatable Edit and Export (CSV, EXCEL, PRINT, PDF, COPY), Cache Clear, XSS protection and many more features.

MOVIETVDB 2020

Link: http://movietvdb.net/

MOVIETVDB is a movie collection site developed in Laravel with huge collections of movies, tv series. Review, Movie share and Getting Movie information's are key features of this site

INSTITUTIONAL MEMORY

2020

Link: https://gitlab.com/rakibdevs/institutional_memory

Sharing institutional memories, attachments, files between fellow classmates, juniors, seniors and teacher. Developed in Laravel.

LARAVEL NUMBER TO BANGLA

2019

Link: https://github.com/rakibdevs/number-to-bangla

Laravel package to convert English numbers to Bangla number or Bangla text, Bangla month name and Bangla Money Format for Laravel

SMART DIAGNOSTIC CENTER

2019

Link: https://lab.rakibhstu.com

Smart diagnostic center management software. Manage receipt's, pathology different types of payment and CO, Due Collection and Expense calculation, print report are the key features of this project

See more projects at https://github.com/rakibhstu/ and https://rakibhstu.com

EDUCATION

B.Sc (Engg.) in Electronics and Communication Engineering	Dinajpur
Hajee Mohammad Danesh Science & Technology University, CGPA 3.03 (4.00)	2014 -2017
HSC , GPA 4.80 (5.00) – Rangpur Govt. College, Rangpur	2013
SSC, GPA 5.00 (5.00) – Gulal Budai High School, Rangpur	2011

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES -

Software Process & Agile process, University of Alberta by Coursera	2020
Project Management Principles & Practices, University of California by Coursera	2020
Android Study Jam, Google Developers Group by Google	2015